## Serena Rampersad

Third year college student studying computer science and mathematics with extensive programming knowledge and strong critical thinking skills. Experience with Agile methodologies and leadership positions. Openminded and excited to contribute to the technology field. serena.rampersad56@gmail.com
(561) 951 – 2098
Royal Palm Beach, Florida 33411
linkedin.com/in/serena-rampersad/
github.com/snrampersad

## **EDUCATION**

<u>Junior</u> at University of South Florida Bachelor of Science in Computer Science GPA: 3.93, *Expected Graduation: May 2021* 

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Study Skills Mentor

USF Academic Success Center, April 2019 – Present

 Supply students with skills and techniques that can be applied to any academic course.

#### Calculus Tutor

USF Academic Success Center, January 2019 – Present

• Assist students with understanding Calculus I, II, and III processes.

### Calculus I Peer Leader

USF Department of Mathematics and Statistics, January 2018 – Present

- Provide students with critical thinking skills applicable to Calculus I material.
- Lead students in a classroom setting through calculus material.

## **SOFT SKILLS**

Teamwork, Problem Solving, Communication, Self – Motivation, Flexibility, Leadership

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Tools: Eclipse, Visual Studio, GitHub <u>Languages:</u> Java, C, C++ (Currently learning: Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript) Other: Agile Methodologies

# EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Women in Computer Science and Engineering (WiCSE)

August 2018 – Present:

 <u>Member</u> – Participate in technical workshops and learn about the development of the technical world.

# <u>Alpha Phi Omega National Service Fraternity – Tau Mu Chapter</u>

August 2017 – Present:

- <u>Sunshine Chair</u> (Spring 2019, Fall 2019)
   Monitors the overall wellbeing of the Chapter and works to uphold positivity throughout the Chapter.
- Membership Vice President (Fall 2018) Responsible for member retention.
   Organized marketing strategies for member recruitment. Increased number of members by sixty percent.
- <u>Service Vice President Assistant</u> (Spring 2018) Organize service opportunities for forty USF students.

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

Summer 2019 (In Progress): Self – teaching HTML, CSS, and JavaScript using Coderbyte. Creating website to showcase skills. See progress under repositories on GitHub.

<u>Summer 2019</u> (In Progress): Self – teaching Python using Coderbyte. Using IDLE (Python 3.7).